Arne Oldberg Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Arne Oldberg Collection circa 1887-1962
ML31.O43
Oldberg, Arne, 1874-1962
around 5,000 items 90 containers 24 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
American composer, musician, and music professor at Northwestern University. The collection contains music scores, parts, and sketches, including holograph and copyist manuscripts, published copies, and photocopies, of Oldberg's works; a considerable amount of correspondence; programs; biographical materials; awards; and a small amount of writings, clippings, financial documents, and photographs.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Bloomfield-Zeisler, Fannie, 1863-1927--Correspondence.; Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1881-1946--Correspondence.; Farwell, Arthur, 1872-1952--Correspondence.; Foote, Arthur, 1853-1937--Correspondence.; Gleason, Frederic Grant, 1848-1903--Correspondence.; Leschetizky, Theodor, 1830-1915--Correspondence.; Liebling, Emil, 1851-1914--Correspondence.; Middelschulte, Wilhelm, 1863-1943--Correspondence.; Oldberg, Arne, 1874-1962--Archives.; Oldberg, Arne, 1874-1962--Correspondence.; Oldberg, Arne, 1874-1962--Manuscripts.; Oldberg, Arne, 1874-1962.; Oldberg, Arne, 1874-1962.; Oldberg, Arne, 1874-1962. Selections.; Oldberg, Oscar, 1846-1913--Correspondence.; Reiner, Fritz, 1888-1963--Correspondence.; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977--Correspondence.; Szell, George, 1897-1970--Correspondence.
Organizations
Chicago Symphony Orchestra.; Northwestern University (Evanston, Ill.)
Subjects
Composers--United States.; Music--Manuscripts--United States.
Form/Genre
Clippings (Information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographic prints.; Programs (Documents)
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift; Elsa and Henry J. Zettelman; 1970.
Custodial History
Arne Oldberg joined the Northwestern University piano faculty in 1897, was appointed professor of music in 1899, and served as professor of piano and composition and director of the graduate department of the Music School until his retirement in 1941. He exerted considerable influence upon the musical life of the Midwest. Oldberg's works were frequently performed by leading orchestras such as the Chicago Symphony and the Hollywood Bowl Orchestra. Among his most notable pupils was the composer, Howard Hanson.
In 1970, Oldberg's daughter Elsa Zettelman and her husband Dr. Henry J. Zettleman donated a large collection of Oldberg's music, correspondence, programs, biographical materials and other related materials to the Library of Congress. Oldberg himself donated two of his works to the Library: the holograph score of A Legend, in 1948 and Sonata for piano, op. 28 in B-flat minor, in the 1940s.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Other Repositories
The Sibley Music Library of the Eastman School of Music contains the Arne Oldberg Collection. Additional Oldberg materials are found in the Edwin A. Fleisher Collection of Orchestral Music at the Free Library of Philadelphia.
Access and Restrictions
The Arne Oldberg Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Patrons are urged to use special caution in handling items found in Box 19, Folder 2 and Box 24, Folder 1.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1874, July 12 Born Youngstown, Ohio
1886-1890 Studied with August Hyllested
1890 Received George M. Pullman Diamond Medal for piano
1892 Graduated with honors, Gottschalk Lyric School, Chicago, Ill.
1893-1895 Studied piano with Theodor Leschetizky, Vienna
1895-1898 Studied composition and orchestration with Wilhelm Middelschulte, Adolph Koelling, and Frederic Grant Gleason, Chicago
1898-1899 Studied composition with Josef Rheinberger, Akademie der Tonkunst, Munich
1899-1941 Professor of Music, professor of Piano and Composition, and director of the Graduate School, Northwestern University, Evanston, Ill.
1900 Married Mary Sloan
1908 Dramatic overture, Paolo and Francesca, op. 21, premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Frederick Stock
1909 Festival overture, op. 29, premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra
1911 Symphony, no. 1, op. 23, version 2, F minor received second prize for symphony, Biennial Prize Competition for American Composers sponsored by National Federation of Music Clubs
1913 Theme and variations for orchestra, op. 19, premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Frederick Stock
1914 Symphonic variations for organ and orchestra, op. 35, premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Frederick Stock
1915 Elected to National Institute of Arts and Letters Symphony, no. 2, op. 34, C minor, received first prize in Biennial Prize Competition for American Composers sponsored by National Federation of Music Clubs Rhapsody, June premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Frederick Stock
1916 Honorary M.A., Northwestern University, Evanston, Ill.
1917 Fantasy, At Night, op. 38 premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Frederick Stock
1921 Canzone, premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Frederick Stock
1927 Symphony no. 3 in F minor, op. 41, premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Frederick Stock
1929 Symphonic variations, op. 42, premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Frederick Stock
1931 Received first prize, Hollywood Bowl Contest for Piano concerto, no. 2, op. 43, A major
1937 Symphonic poem, The Sea, op. 47, premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Hans Lange
1938 Fantasia in B minor, op. 48, premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Frederick Stock
1939 Elected honorary member, Iota Chapter of Sinfonia Fraternity
1940 Awarded Honorary Life Membership, Northwestern University Alumni Association
1941 Retired from Northwestern University Andante cantabile, op. 50 premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Nicolai Malko
1943 Symphony no. 4 in B minor, op. 50 premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Hans Lange
1946 Concerto for violin in D minor, op. 46, premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of Désiré Defauw
1950 Symphony no. 5 in E minor, op. 54 premiered by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, under the direction of George Szell
1959 Awarded Ohioana Career Medal in Music for composing and teaching achievements
1962, Feb. 17 Died, Evanston, Ill.
Scope and Content Note
Oldberg's musical oeuvre, as represented in the collection, includes seven symphonies, three piano concertos, several large orchestral works, chamber works, solo piano pieces as well as vocal works. These works span his student days to just before his death and represent, by far, the largest series in the collection. Most of the works contain opus numbers but the numbering system is not always consistent; several pieces share opus numbers, e.g.: the Quintet, 2 violins, viola, cello, piano, op. 24, c# minor and Concertino for piano and chamber orchestra, op. 24; the Sinfonia op. 48 and the Sonata for violin/cello and piano op. 48 and op. 48a; as well as the Ballade op. 53 and the Trois Chansons Françaises, op. 53. An index to the musical compositions and opus numbers is found in appendix A.
Some of Oldberg's works exist in several versions, e.g. Symphony number one, the violin sonata, the cello sonata, and the Ballade, op. 53. Other pieces lack an opus number entirely, a situation which Oldberg's son, Karl, later attempted to correct by creating "KO" numbers for the unnumbered pieces. Orchestral parts, whether in Oldberg's hand, in that of a copyist, or photocopies, are included for most works. Included among the music are two folders of music composed by Arne Oldberg's father, Oscar.
Among the notebooks in the collection are numerous harmony and counterpoint studies, as well as copies of works by Rheinberger, all dating from Oldberg's student days. Sketchbooks also exist from Oldberg's days as a professor of composition at Northwestern University.
The programs document performances of Oldberg's pieces by a number of American orchestras from 1909 to 1958, most notably the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, though there are some programs from the Minneapolis Symphony, the Philadelphia Orchestra, and the Hollywood Bowl Orchestra.
Oldberg's correspondence, once classed as ML 94.055, is now included with the collection. This correspondence details his years in Europe as a student, his involvement with the Chicago Manuscript Society, of which he was a founding member, as well as his later activities as composer and instructor. There is considerable correspondence from Oldberg's father Oscar Oldberg. Notable correspondents include Fannie Bloomfield-Zeisler, Charles Wakefield Cadman, Arthur Farwell, Arthur Foote, Frederic Grant Gleason, Theodor Leschetizky, Emil Liebling, Wilhelm Middelschulte, Fritz Reiner, George Szell, and Leopold Stokowski.
In addition, there are awards; biographical material; small amounts of photographs, clippings, financial materials, and writings; and other miscellaneous materials.
Peter Schmelz, 1995 Junior Fellow
Robert Saladini, Music Specialist
Organization of the Arne Oldberg Collection
The Arne Oldberg Collection is organized in ten series:
Music,
Correspondence, circa 1892-1962
Biographical Materials
Writings
Photographs
Programs, 1891-1961
Financial Materials
Clippings
Awards and Certificates
Miscellany, circa 1887-circa 1950
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006569272
Container List
- Music (Box 1-78, 81-85)
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Holograph sketches in pencil; 9 p. (Box-folder 1/1)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Holograph sketch score in pencil; 57 p. (Box-folder 1/2)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Holograph full score; 46 p. (Box-folder 1/3)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Photocopy of holograph full score; 41 p. (Box-folder 84/1)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Autograph bass clarinet part (Box-folder 1/4)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Violin parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 1/5)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Viola, cello, and bass parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 1/6)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Flute, piccolo, oboe, and English horn parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 1/7)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Clarinet and bassoon parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 1/8)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Holograph bass clarinet part (Box-folder 1/9)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Holograph horn I-IV and trumpet I-III parts (Box-folder 1/10)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Horn I-IV and trumpet I-III parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 1/11)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Trombone and tuba parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 1/12)
  - "At night," Fantasy for orchestra, op. 38, Percussion, harp, and celesta parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Ballade for orchestra, op. 53, Piano and quintet arrangement, holograph full score; 33 p. (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Ballade for orchestra, op. 53, Holograph piano score; 15 p. (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Ballade for orchestra, op. 53, Photocopy of holograph piano score; 16 p. (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Ballade for orchestra, op. 53, Photocopy of holograph violin I, violin II, viola, cello, and bass parts (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Canzone see Symphony no. 3, II. Canzone
  - Concertino for piano and chamber orchestra, op. 24, Transparencies of holograph two piano score; 25 p. (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Concertino for piano and chamber orchestra, op. 24, Transparencies of holograph string parts (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46, Holograph full score (cello version); 129 p. (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46, Photocopy of holograph full score; 127 p. (Box-folder 84/2)
  - Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46, Holograph piano and cello score in ink with pencil corrections; 41 p. (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46, Transparencies of holograph piano-violin/cello score; 66 p. (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46, Transparencies of holograph piano-violin/cello score; 63 p. (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46, Transparencies of holograph solo cello part (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46, Photocopy and transparencies of holograph solo violin part (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46, Transparencies of holograph string parts (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46, Transparencies of holograph woodwind parts (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Concerto (all' antico) for violin or cello and orchestra, op. 46, Transparencies of holograph brass, percussion, and harp parts (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Holograph two piano sketch; 94 p. (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Holograph two piano fragments, including "Passages for piano, 1st movement" and "Cadenza" in pencil and ink; 15 p.; Originally laid in with box 3, folder 5. (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Photocopy of holograph two piano score; 86 p. (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Holograph full score; pp. 1-56 (folder one of three) (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Holograph full score; pp. 57-148 (folder two of three) (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Holograph full score; pp. 149-257 (folder three of three) (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Transparencies of holograph full score; 126 p. (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Transparencies of holograph two piano score; 86 p. (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Printed two piano score, with corrections and inserts by Oldberg; 73 p.; Published by G. Schirmer Inc., 1907. (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Printed two piano score, 73 p. (copy one); Newton Center, Mass.: The Wa-Wan Press, 1907. (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Printed two piano score, 73 p. (copy two); Newton Center, Mass.: The Wa-Wan Press, 1907. (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Printed two piano score, 73 p.; Published by G. Schirmer Inc., 1907. (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Holograph flute parts (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Flute, oboe, clarinet, and bassoon parts, copyist's manuscript; Holograph clarinet I, p. 3 and 4 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Horn and trumpet parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Trombone and percussion parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Holograph full score; 253 p. (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Holograph sketch score in pencil and ink; 212 p. (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, String parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, First violin parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Second violin parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Viola parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 1, op. 17, G minor, Cello and bass parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Holograph full score in black ink, with annotations in blue and red pencil; 181 p. (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Photocopy of holograph two piano score; 89 p. (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Holograph two piano score, portion of movement III; 3 p. (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Photocopy of holograph full score; 138 p. (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Transparencies of holograph full score; 138 p. (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Transparencies of holograph two piano score; 89 p. (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Violin parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Viola, cello, and bass parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Flute, oboe, and clarinet parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Bassoon and horn parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Trumpet, trombone, and percussion parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, First violin parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Second violin parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Viola parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 2, op. 43, Cello and bass parts, copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Photocopy of holograph full score; 109 p. (copy one) (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Photocopy of holograph full score; 109 p. (copy two) (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Photocopy of holograph two piano score; 52 p. (copy one) (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Photocopy of holograph two piano score; 52 p. (copy two) (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Holograph two piano score; 52 p. (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Transparencies of holograph two piano score; 52 p. (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Transparencies of holograph full score; 109 p. (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Transparencies of holograph string parts (Box-folder 11/4)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Holograph cello and bass parts (Box-folder 11/5)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Holograph woodwind parts (Box-folder 11/6)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Holograph brass and percussion parts (Box-folder 11/7)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Photocopy of holograph violin parts (Box-folder 11/8)
  - Concerto for piano and orchestra, no. 3, op. 52, Photocopy of holograph viola, cello, and bass parts (Box-folder 11/9)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Holograph full score; 108 p. and Choral finale; 31 p. (Box-folder 12/1)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Photocopy of holograph full score; 74 p. (Box-folder 85/1)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Photocopy of holograph piano score (two copies); p. 2-13 and Choral finale; p. 2-7 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Printed edition, copyright 1909, by Arne Oldberg; p. 3-11; Pencil annotations by Oldberg. (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Photocopy of holograph piano score; p. 2-7 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Incomplete holograph piano score; p. 2-13 (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Holograph chorus sketch score in pencil; 8 p. (Box-folder 12/6)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Transparencies of holograph full score; 74 p., with one page of sketches (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Transparencies of holograph piano score and choral score (choral finale); 13 p. and Choral finale; 7 p. (Box-folder 12/8)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Holograph violin II part (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Transparencies of string parts in copyist's hand (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Transparencies of woodwind parts in copyist's hand (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Transparencies of brass and percussion parts in copyist's hand (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Copyist's manuscript and photocopies of first violin parts (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Copyist's manuscript and photocopies of second violin parts (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Copyist's manuscript and photocopies of viola parts (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Copyist's manuscript and photocopies of cello and bass parts (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Copyist's manuscript of flute and oboe parts (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Copyist's manuscript and photocopies of clarinet and bassoon parts (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Copyist's manuscript and photocopies of horn parts (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Copyist's manuscript of trumpet, trombone, and tuba parts (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Festival overture, op. 29, Copyist's manuscript and photocopies of percussion, celesta, and organ parts (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Four outdoor songs for contralto and orchestra, op. 22
    - Four outdoor songs for contralto and orchestra, op. 22, Autograph piano-vocal score; 35 p. (Box-folder 15/1)
    - The hunters horn, op. 22, no. 4, Holograph piano score in ink with pencil sketches at end; 8 p. (Box-folder 15/2)
    - The hunter's horn, op. 22, no. 4, Incomplete holograph full score; 1 p. (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Four outdoor songs for contralto and orchestra, op. 22, nos. 1-3, Autograph full score; 65 p. (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Four outdoor songs, nos. 1, 2, and 4, Copyist's piano vocal scores; God's miracle of May, op. 22, no. 1; 12 p. God's miracle of May, op. 22, no. 1; 10 p. A flirt, op. 22, no. 2; 15 p. The hunter's horn, op. 22, no. 4; 7 p. (Box-folder 15/5)
  - "June," rhapsody, op. 36, Holograph full score; 62 p. (Box-folder 15/5b)
  - "June," rhapsody, op. 36, Copyist's violin parts (Box-folder 15/6)
  - "June," rhapsody, op. 36, Copyist's viola, cello, and bass parts (Box-folder 15/7)
  - "June," rhapsody, op. 36, Copyist's flute, oboe, and English horn parts (Holograph sections of flute and oboe parts) (Box-folder 15/8)
  - "June," rhapsody, op. 36, Copyist's clarinet and bassoon parts (Holograph sections of clarinet and bassoon parts) (Box-folder 15/9)
  - "June," rhapsody, op. 36, Holograph horn and trumpet parts (Box-folder 15/10)
  - "June," rhapsody, op. 36, Copyist's trombone, tuba, and percussion parts (Box-folder 15/11)